We've got a couple of conversation lined
up next. Nigel, take it away. All right.
Let's focus on ICICI Lombard. They
reported a rather good set of numbers in
the fourth quarter. The gross return
premium was up at close to 17%. We're
joined by Mr. Gopal Balachandran, the
chief financial officer at ICICI
Lombard, who joins in on the show.
Hi, sir. Good morning. Good to see you
in
Well, take us about the outlook for FY27
for the industry on the whole. What kind
of growth are you looking at? And for
ICICI Lombard, what's the growth number
that you're penciling in?
Well, Nigel, good morning and good
morning to all your viewers.
I'm always happy to kind of connect to
the channel.
So, honestly, I think if you look at
before I can specifically answer on how
do we look at FY27, I think we have
always maintained that
from an ICICI Lombard standpoint, we
will continue to see
opportunities of growing the book
profitably. And that's the thought
process that we get into for FY27.
And therefore, from the thought process
standpoint, I think the way we have
always looked at writing businesses to
try and see how we can continue to
accrete market share.
And the range that we have talked talked
about in terms of trying to get a delta
vis-a-vis the industry at an aggregate
level all lines put together is 100 to
200 basis points. So, that's the number
that we would kind of go with when we
get into FY27. Try and see if we can
continue to have an alpha over the
industry growth numbers of 100 to 200
basis points.
>> All right. So, you're expecting to
outgrow the industry uh growth number.
Got that.
Uh you know, do you expect the combined
ratio
to be sub 100% odd mark in FY27? Well,
let me again just put that in context. I
think because our business is obviously
kind of cyclical and therefore to that
extent, obviously, you get to see
experiences play out between different
time cycles. And this is what we put out
also in the investor earnings call that
we had last evening. If you look at the
10-year average,
ICICI Lombard's combined has been about
102.9%.
This is in the last 10-year time cycle.
Industry combined ratio has been 115%.
So, the delta that we have had vis-a-vis
the industry has always been in excess
of 10 percentage points. And
specifically to your point on how do we
see the trajectory of combined play out.
If you look at the last 2-3 years in
specific, every year we have been able
to kind of see an improvement in our
combined ratios on a year-on-year basis.
And that is the same thought process
that we would want to continue to
exhibit even as we get into FY27. And
more More than the combined, the other
metric that we have always spoken to all
of you is to try and see if we can
sustain that ROE trajectory of 18 to 20%
and that's also a number that got
exhibited even for the current year gone
by. Mhm.
Uh thank you very much sir for waiting
by. This is Rima here. Can you tell us
what specifically led to the improvement
in the combined ratio because it
declined from 105% in Q3 to 101.2%
in Q4. What were the factors which drove
it?
Uh and for FY27, what is the number that
you're looking at? Do you get back to
say 101%
or would it be between 100 to 101%?
I'll take the second part first. So,
Rima, I think we have always kind of put
this in the context of how the market
plays out. Uh which is the reason I kind
of called out that long-term average of
the industry combined vis-a-vis let's
say ICICI Lombard's combined trajectory.
Uh so, we will obviously wait and see
how the market responds to in FY27 from
a combined ratio standpoint. Our thought
process is as I said, we should try and
see if
if we can continue to have that delta of
more than 10 percentage point difference
between uh the industry combined and
let's say ICICI Lombard's
numbers. And now coming back to the
specific point on the year gone by in
terms of what has led to the
improvement, uh honestly, I think the
way we would look at it is obviously to
try try and look at over long cycles. Uh
but definitely on a year-on-year basis
on a year-on-year basis, actually, we
have seen an improvement in combined on
an end basis from 102.6 to 102.4.
Uh so, again, there's been a it's been
an improvement in the overall combined
aided by uh an all across
clear
growth in top line coming from the
preferred lines of businesses. And more
importantly, what we have been able to
exhibit is a better loss experience. And
obviously, we have been able to kind of
also make sure that we're able to create
efficiencies in businesses.
Okay.
Uh and can you break that up in terms of
growth for the individual sectors
because you're guiding for a high single
digit kind of growth for motor next year
and you've generally outperformed. Does
that mean we're looking at a double
digit growth for the motor segment,
which is I think close to about 50% of
your overall revenues? And then if you
could talk about health and even the
fire segment. Uh where
you've highlighted discounting pricing
in fire insurance renewals starting 1st
of April. So, give us an outlook and
overview and trajectory on each of your
segments.
Well, let's take the let's take each of
the segments. I think if you look at
motor, I think what we have always done
is uh depending on how the market
environment has played out is how we
have been able to go all in in terms of
being able to gain incremental market
share. And that is exactly exactly what
got exhibited in the second half of this
year. Uh in motor, the industry grew at
about 10%. We were able to grow at about
about 15%. And this strong momentum that
we have seen in the second half of this
year is something that we are quite
excited to see how hopefully that will
kind of play through even as we get into
FY27. Uh obviously, what aids growth in
motor is a combination of what you
rightly said, which is new vehicle
sales. And two and more importantly,
from an ICICI Lombard standpoint, we
have also kind of stayed focused on
improving our retention numbers uh
in terms of how many customers we are
able to retain. So, there again, in the
year gone by, we have actually seen an
improvement of almost anywhere between 3
to 5 percentage points in motor as a
category. So, that's Those are the two
things that we will watch for in terms
of how one one is looking at positioning
to write growth in FY27 for motor. On
health, I think by far and more
specifically, I will confine to retail
health. Uh retail health has been by far
one of the fastest growing segment at an
industry level consistently over the
last 5 to 6 years. We honestly see with
this renewed
renewed regulatory changes and reforms
getting exhibited, the awareness on
health will be continuing one and we
will see even FY27 exhibiting uh uh
significantly better outlook from a
market perspective. And within that,
obviously, from an ICICI Lombard
standpoint, we will want to continue to
accrete market share as what we have
done in the year gone by. In the year
gone by on retail health, our market
share improved from 3.3 to 4.1%. So,
honestly, we would want to kind of make
sure that we are able to continue to
exhibit incremental market share
accretion in the retail health space.
Commercial lines,
and within that, the segment that we
spoke about on fire, at this point of
time, fire we are seeing a bit elevated
levels of competitive intensity. And
hence, we will be slightly watchful and
guarded in terms of how we want to
position our book.
But beyond fire, there equally other
lines in the commercial lines space
which we think will be viable from an
underwriting perspective and that's
something that we will go after.
All right. Very quickly, sir, when does
the motor price revision come about in
FY27 if you could tell us when and what
is the quantum you're working with?
Honestly, at this point of time, I think
that's something that we believe is
something that is required from a market
perspective. Okay. And hence, we will
wait for as and when the announcement
happens, I think we will be able to talk
specifics on the extent of change what
comes through. Okay.
>> But from an industry standpoint, I think
we are definitely very very hopeful of a
motor third-party price increase to
happen. What is the quantum that you're
expecting?
Honestly, Nigel, at this point of time,
which is where I said, once the
announcement happens, we will be able to
kind of talk something more specifics
around that. All right. What about the
draft commission regulations? There has
been a lot of to and fro on that front
and my colleague Yash has been on top of
that. By when do you expect that to come
about?
Again,
again, the direction is absolutely
correct. And honestly, we will again My
response will be the same as what I
mentioned for motor third-party. I think
we will obviously wait for the
guidelines to get announced and then
obviously, we will be able to talk
something more specific around those.
All right.
We'll leave [clears throat] it there.
Thank you very much. Good speaking with
you and appreciate your time here on
CNBC-TV18.